A Finding Aid to the National Arts Club Records, 1898-1960, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Printed Matter, 1893-1960, undated; Series 8; Archival Resource Key
  - Non-National Arts Club Printed Matter, 1893-1959, undated; 8.2; Archival Resource Key
    - Club Members of New York, vol. 8, 1924; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4262, Frame 557-568)
    - By and About NAC Members, Archival Resource Key (Reel 4262, Frame 569-646)
    - About Gramercy Park, Archival Resource Key (Reel 4262, Frame 647-662)
    - Exhibition Announcements, Catalogs, etc., 1916-1955, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4262, Frame 663-716)
    - Other Art Organizations, Archival Resource Key (Reel 4262, Frame 717-738)
    - Miscellaneous, Art Matters, Archival Resource Key (Reel 4262, Frame 739-762)
    - Miscellaneous, Not Art Matters, Archival Resource Key (Reel Unfilmed)
    - Loose Clippings, 1893-1959, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4262, Frame 764-1090)
- Scrapbooks, 1898-1940; Series 9; Archival Resource Key
  This series contains seventeen scrapbooks complied by the National Arts Club. They include Annual Club Record, 1908-1912 (3 volumes); National Arts Club Printed Matter, 1898-1940 (7 volumes); and Clippings, 1912-1940 (7 volumes). Titles of NAC exhibition catalogs are noted. For additional records in this category see also Series 8: Printed Matter and Appendix A.
  The series is organized into three subseries:
  9.1: Annual Club Record, 1898-1912
  9.2: National Arts Club Printed Matter, 1898-1940
  9.3: Clippings, 1912-1940
  - Annual Club Record, 1898-1912; 9.1; Archival Resource Key
    These scrapbooks contain a variety of NAC printed matter, including Bulletin, the yearbook, membership lists, by-laws, constitution, house rules, catalogs, invitations, and programs; clippings regarding entertainments and club social events, exhibitions, obituaries, and articles about members.
    - Volume 1, 1898-1909; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4263, Frame 6-158)
      Members Fall Sketch Exhibition, Oct. 21- Nov. 7, 1908
      International Exhibition of Pictorial Photography, Feb. 2-20, 1909
      John W. Alexander Retrospective, Feb. 23-March 17, 1909
    - Volume 2 [target omitted], 1909-1910; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4263, Frame 159-208)
      Fourth Annual Exhibition of Books of the Year, Nov. 3-26, 1909
      Exhibition of the Former Students of the Art Students League, May 1910
    - Volume 3, 1911-1912; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4263, Frame 209-319)
      First Annual Exhibition of Artist Life Members, Jan. 5-Feb. 3, 1911
      Walter Shirlaw Memorial, March 8-April 5, 1911
      Third Annual Exhibition of Advertising Art, Oct.20-Nov. 19, [1911?]
      Group Exhibition, April 1911
      First Prize Exhibition of Artist Life Members, Jan. 3-28, 1912
      Otto Walter Beck, Jan. 31-Feb. 18, 1912
      Etchings of E. T. Hurley, Feb. 21-March 10, 1912
      National Park Pictures Collected and Exhibited by the Department of the Interior, March 13-20, 1912
      Exhibition of Paintings, Embroideries and Tapestries from the Collection of Mr. Emerson McMillan, April 4-21, 1912
      Exhibition of Original Dickens and Thackeray Drawings by Harry Furniss, April 24-May 4, 1912
      Special Sculpture Exhibition, May 8-June 1, 1912
  - National Arts Club Printed Matter, 1898-1940; 9.2; Archival Resource Key
    - Volume 4, 1898-1907; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4263, Frame 321-586)
      Portraits of Napoleon owned by John Leonard Dudley, Jan. 1903
      Loan Exhibition of Pictures by Eminent American Painters, Jan. 5-16, 1904
      Loan Exhibition of Pictures by American Figure Painters, March 2-15, 1904
      Loan Exhibition of Pictures by Robert Henri, William Glackens, George Luks, Arthur B. Davies, and Maurice Prendergast, Jan. 5-16, 1904
      Loan Exhibition of Pictures by Some Boston Artists, April 5-15, 1904
      Loan Exhibition of Pictures by Old Masters, from Durand-Ruel, April 9-30, 1904
      Loan Exhibition of Paintings, Water Colors and Drawings by John La Farge, May 3-14, 1904
      Municipal Art Society Exhibit of Poster Designs, April 2-14, 1906
      Opening Exhibition of American Paintings from the Collection of Mr. William T. Evans, Nov. 8-18, 1906
      Exhibition by Some American Artists, Dec. 18, 1906-Jan. 1, 1907
      Modern German Paintings from the Collection of Hugo Reisinger, Jan. 12-Feb. 1, 1907
      Sixth Annual Exhibition of the Municipal Art Society of New York, March 13-31, 1907
      Wood-Engravings of Timothy Cole made for Century Magazine, May, 1907
      Exhibitions of Artists' Preliminary Sketches, May 1907
      Fall Exhibition of Sketches by Members, Oct. 16-Nov. 16, 1907
    - Volume 5, 1906-1911; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4263, Frame 587-744)
      Exhibition of Some American Artists, Dec. 18, 1906-Jan. 18, 1907
      Exhibition of Artists' Preliminary Sketches, May 1907
      Contemporary Paintings, Feb. 1-15, 1908
      Contemporary Art, Jan. 4-25, 1908
      Special Exhibition of Members' Work, April 2-25, 1908
      Paintings Loaned by C. C. Ruthrauff, April 25-May 15, 1908
      Members' Special Exhibition, April 15-May 8, 1908
      Members' Fall Sketch Exhibition, Oct. 21-Nov. 7, 1908
      Fourth Annual Book Exhibition, Nov. 3-26, 1909
      Louis Mark of Budapest, March 2-28, [1910?]
      Alfred East of London, April 6-30, 1910
      Exhibition of Former Students of the Art Students League, May 4-Oct. 10, 1910
      Third Annual Exhibition of Advertising Art, Oct. 20-Nov. 1,1910
      Walter Shirlaw Memorial Exhibition, March 8-April 5, 1911
      Group Exhibition of Paintings by William R. Derrick, Reynolds Beal, Gifford Beal, and Frederick J. Waugh, April 1911
    - Volume 5, cont., Archival Resource Key (Reel 4264, Frame 7-184)
    - Volume 6, 1911-1917; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4264, Frame 186-706)
      Special Prize Exhibition, Jan. 3-28, 1912
      Sculpture Exhibition, May 8-June 1, 1912
      Third Special Exhibition of the Society of Illustrators, Oct.-Nov. 1912
      Exhibition of Works by the Late Frederick Warren Freer, Feb. 12-March 9, 1913
      Work of Painter, Sculptor, and Architect Members, Jan. 7-Feb. 1, 1914
      Contemporary Art, Feb. 5-March 7, 1914
      Portraits, March 3-24, 1915
      Work of Painter Members, Jan. 5-18, 1916
      Forty-ninth Annual Exhibition of the American Water Color Society, Feb. 3-27, 1916
      Loan Exhibition of Portraits of Academicians and Associates Selected from the Permanent Collection of the National Academy of Design, March 2-25, 1916
      One Hundred American Paintings by the American Institute of Graphic Arts, March 28-April 14, 1916
      Exhibition of American Prints, March 28-April 14, 1916
      Members' Summer Sketch Exhibition, June-Aug. 1916
      Annual Exhibition of the Work of Artist Members, Jan. 4-26, 1917
      Fiftieth Annual Exhibition of the American Water Color Society, Feb. 1-24, 1917
      Etchings by Contemporary Artists, under the auspices of the American Institute of Graphic Arts, Feb. 28-March 23, 1917
      Paintings by Boston Artists, March 29-April 28, 1917
      Members' Annual Sketch Exhibition, May-Sept. 1917
    - Volume 7, 1917-1924; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4264, Frame 707-1073)
      The Netherlands Exhibition, Oct. 3-31, 1917
      Annual Exhibition of the Work of Artist Members, Jan. 3-Feb. 1, 1918
      Fifty-first Annual Exhibition of the American Water Color Society, Feb. 7-March 1, 1918
      Summer Sketch Exhibition, June-Oct. 1918
      Retrospective Exhibition of Work of Artist Life Members, Jan. 8-31, 1919
      Special Exhibition of the Society of Illustrators, April 2-May 3, 1919
      Members' Annual Sketch Exhibition, May-Oct. 1919
      Annual Exhibition of Painter and Sculptor Members, Jan. 7-30, 1920
      Special Exhibition of the Society of Illustrators, March 31-April 16, 1920
      Members' Summer Exhibition of Sketches and Small Sculpture, Jun-Oct. 1920
      Exhibition of Art Expression by Club Members, Dec. 1-29, 1920
      Annual Prize Exhibition, Jan. 5-27, 1921
      First Annual Exhibition of the Art Directors Club of New York, March 2-13, 1921
      Humorists Exhibition, Dec. 7-30, 1921
      Annual Prize Exhibition of Painter and Sculptor Members, Jan. 5-28, 1922
      Exhibition of Paintings by Charles C. Curran, Franklin deHaven, George Glenn Newell, Harry Watrous, Feb. 15-March 5, 1922
      Loan Exhibition of American Paintings Owned by Club Members, April 5-30, 1922
      Annual Prize Exhibition of Painter and Sculptor Members, June 5-28, 1922
      Summer Exhibition of Members' Work, May-Oct. 1922
      Special Exhibition of Members' Work, Dec. 6-29, 1922
      Annual Prize Exhibition, Jan. 10-Feb. 10, 1923
      Humorists Exhibition, Feb. 14-March 3, 1923
      Group Exhibition: Hayley Lever, Leon Dabo, William R. Derrick, Charles P. Gruppe, Charles Robert Patterson, April 1923
      Exhibition of Living American Etchers, Dec. 12-29, 1923
      Members' Annual Exhibition, Jan. 9-Feb. 2, 1924
      Exhibition of Sculpture, March 5-29, 1924
      Exhibition of Books Illustrating the History of Printing, April 30-May 15, 1924
    - Volume 7, cont., Archival Resource Key (Reel 4265, Frame 7-316)
    - Volume 8, 1924-1932; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4265, Frame 318-1159)
      Exhibition of Art Expression by Club Members, Dec. 1-29, 1924
      Members' Annual Exhibition, Jan. 7-31, 1925
      Autograph Letters with Accompanying Portraits of Authors, Statesmen, Artists, etc., Feb. 23-March 7, 1925
      Second Annual Exhibition of Living American Etchers, Dec. 10-27, 1924
      Special Exhibition of Lithographs, Woodblocks, and Linoleum Cuts, April 8-May 9, 1925
      Exhibition of Living American Etchers, Dec. 3-20, 1925
      Members' Annual Exhibition, Jan. 13-Feb. 6, 1926
      Special Group Exhibition, Feb. 10-27, 1926
      Special Exhibition of Copies of Old Masters, March 3-27, 1926
      Special Exhibition of Architecture, Sculpture, and Decorative Painting, April 7-May 7, 1926
      Fifth Annual Exhibition of the Brooklyn Society of Etchers, May 1926
      Exhibition of Volkbehr Collection of Incunabula, Aug. 23-Sept. 30, 1926
      Summer Exhibition, 1926
      Fourth Annual Exhibition of Living American Etchers, Dec. 2-22, 1926
      Members' Annual Exhibition, Jan. 5-29, 1927
      Exhibition and Auction of Works of Art by Artist Members, Feb. 11-27, 1927
      Invited Exhibition of Distinguished American Painters, March 2-21, 1927
      Fifth Annual Exhibition of Living American Etchers, Dec. 7-24, 1927
      Norse Pictorial Weavings by Mrs. Berthea Aske Bergh, April 6-29, 1928
      Members' Annual Exhibition, Feb. 8-29, 1928
      Sixth Annual Exhibition of Living American Etchers, Feb. 13-March 8, 1928
      Exhibition of Decorative Arts, March 8-31, 1928
      Junior Artist Members, April 4-20, 1928
      Members' Annual Exhibition, Jan. 8-Feb. 1, 1929
      Loan Exhibition of Italian Primitives from the Collection of Richard M. Hurd, March 1929
      Junior Artist Members, April 3-26, 1929
      Summer Exhibition of Painter Life Members, May 1-Oct. 1, 1929
      Exhibition of Decorative Arts, Dec. 4-26, 1929
      Members' Annual Exhibition, Jan. 8-Feb. 1, 1930
      Seventh Annual Exhibition of Living American Etchers, Feb. 5-28, 1930
      Junior Artist Members, March 5-28, 1930
      Members' Exhibition, April 16-Sept. 30, 1930
      Eighth Annual Exhibition of Living American Etchers, Dec. 3-26, 1930
      New York Water Color Club Exhibition, April 1-25, 1931
      Gramercy Park Centenary Celebration Exhibition, May 2-29, 1931
      Members' Annual Exhibition, Jan. 7-Feb. 6, 1931
      Junior Artists, March 4-27, 1931
      Members' Exhibition, June 3-Oct. 1, 1931
      Members' Exhibition, Jan. 6-13, 1932
      Exhibition of Drawings by Artist Members, Feb. 3-27, 1932
      Junior Artist Members, March 2-26, 1932
      Exhibition and Auction of Works of Art by Artist Members, March 13-April 15, 1932
      Exhibition by a Group of New York Art Schools, April 20-30. 1932
      Members' Exhibition, May 4-Oct. 1, 1932
    - Volume 8, cont., Archival Resource Key (Reel 4266, Frame 7-60)
    - Volume 9, 1933-1937; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4266, Frame 62-186)
      Members' Annual Exhibition, Jan. 4-27, 1933
      Junior Artist Members, March 1-31, 1933
      Society of Illustrators, April 5-22, 1933
      Members Exhibition, May 3-Oct. 1, 1933
      Memorial Exhibition, Group of Former Painter and Sculptor Members: Max Bohm, Emil Carlsen, Charles Hawthorne, Robert Henri, Karl Bitter, Solon Borglum, Daniel Chester French, Edmund Quinn, Jan. 31-March 2, 1934
      Junior Artist Members, March 7-29, 1934
      Thirty-second Annual Exhibition of the Society of Illustrators, April 4-27, 1934
      Members' Exhibition of Small Paintings and Sculpture, May 2-30, 1934
      Members' Annual Exhibition, Jan. 9-Feb. 1, 1935
      Members' No-Jury Exhibition, Feb. 6-March 2, 1935
      Junior Artist Members, March 6-29, 1935
      Loan Exhibition of Works of Art owned by Artist Members, April 3-27, 1935
      Members' Annual Exhibition, Jan. 8-31, 1936
      Junior Artist Members, March 4-27, 1936
      Exhibition of Neighboring Art Organizations, April 1-May 1, 1936
      First Annual Exhibition of Pictorial Photography, by Pictorial Forum, May 6-30, 1936
      Members' Annual Exhibition, Jan. 6-29, 1937
      Exhibition by the Younger Artists Group, March 3-26, 1937
      Second Exhibition of Neighboring Art Organizations, March 31-April 28, 1937
    - Volume 10, 1937-1940; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4266, Frame 187-397)
      Members' Exhibition of Small Paintings, in Black and White, Dec. 8-25, 1937
      Members' Annual Exhibition, Jan. 12-Feb., 1938
      Third Exhibition of Neighboring Art Organizations, March 14-April 2, 1938
      Exhibition of the Younger Artists Group, April 6-20, 1938
      Exhibition of a Group of Former Painter and Sculptor Members, Jan. 12-27, 1939
      Members' Annual Exhibition, Feb. 1-25, 1939
      Flower Paintings, March 1-31, 1939
      Fourth Annual Exhibition of Neighboring Art Organizations, April 5-21, 1939
      Annual Junior Members' Exhibition, May 10-24, 1939
      Selected Works by Deceased Artists from the National Arts Club's Permanent Collection, June-Oct. 1939
      Special Exhibition of the Paintings of Junior Members, Oct. 18-28, 1939
      Christmas Sale of Paintings, Drawing, Photographs, and Sculpture by Junior Members, Dec. 4-25, 1939
      Members' Annual Exhibition, Jan. 3-19, 1940
      Distinguished Exhibition of the Work of Living American Painters, Non-Members, Jan. 24-Feb. 9, 1940
      Ceramics, Feb. 14-29, 1940
      Annual Junior Members' Exhibition, April 3-19, 1940
      Flower and Still Life Paintings, April 24-May 3, 1940
  - Clippings, 1912-1940; 9.3; Archival Resource Key
    In addition to clippings, some volumes in this subseries also contain a small number of photographs and catalogs of commercial galleries in New York City.
    - Volume 11, 1912-1917; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4266, Frame 398-629)
    - Volume 12, 1916-1926; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4266, Frame 631-792)
    - Volume 12, 1916-1926, cont.; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4267, Frame 7-367)
    - Volume 13, 1925-1928; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4267, Frame 368-908)
    - Volume 14, 1929-1932; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4267, Frame 910-1149)
    - Volume 14, 1929-1932, cont.; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4268, Frame 7-316)
    - Volume 15, 1932-1933; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4268, Frame 317-502)
    - Volume 16, 1934-1936; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4268, Frame 503-659)
    - Volume 17, 1936-1940; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4268, Frame 660-935)